DEACON MOSLEY

ABOUT

IT Specialist with over 13 years of professional experience in information technology administration, design, security, and development. 7+ years as a Microsoft SQL Server database administrator. Broad skill set spanning infrastructure, network, development, and support.

ACHIEVEMENT S & SKILLS

DATABASE ADMINISTRATION

Seven years as a Microsoft SQL Server DBA in the energy industry. Development of Integration Services Packages for data warehouse and other applications, Report Development with SQL Server Reporting Services. Backup planning, monitoring, and testing. In-house development and vendor database customization including DDL, DML, stored procedures, triggers, and ETL operations. Performance and alert monitoring with tuning and incident response, troubleshooting, and resolution.

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

13+ years administration of Microsoft Windows. Database administration of Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, Sybase, MySQL, and PostreSQL. Backup management, planning, and testing. Domain and application access control. Security systems management including firewalls, intrusion prevention systems, and malware identification and removal. Update/upgrade planning, testing. Network management of DNS, DHCP, aliases, gateway rules, Wi-Fi, and VPN. Project proposals, planning, and implementation. Intranet and webmaster administration.

DEVELOPMENT

7 years of SQL development using T-SQL, OpenQuery, Integration Services, Reporting Services, and PowerShell. Administrative tool development in Basic, Java, PowerShell, bat files, Bash, Korn. Web development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and content management systems. Intermediate level Python development in tool, web, and analytics.

WORK HISTORY

CONTRACT IT CONSULTANT (ETC), TULSA, OK

September 2019 - Present

Provide on-site and remote technical support for residential and small business clients. Recommend solutions for issues and new expansion.

CONTRACT, CECIL KAYE ENTERPRISES, TULSA, OK

July 2019 - Present

Provide general IT support and new implementation of website and automating workflows. Occasionally assist with housekeeping of short-term rentals and some maintenance/handyman work.

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR III, WPX ENERGY, TULSA, OK

October 2012 - June 2019

SQL Server DBA, administrator for 500+ databases across ~50 instances in energy industry. Backup and recovery, Integration Services, Reporting Services, stored procedures, scripting, and vendor database customizations.

CONTRACT AND FREELANCE, TULSA, OK

September 2010 – October 2012

Contract Examples:

- Exchange upgrade and migration for a medical facility in Phoenix,
 Δ7
- Information security access control at medical facility in Tulsa, OK
- Information security access control at energy company in Tulsa, OK

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR, GEAR PRODUCTS, TULSA, OK

January 2007 - September 2009

Performed all functions in IT department including the administration of:

- local network LAN traffic management, gateway, VPN, DNS, DHCP
- data security Access control and file management, antivirus, IPS
- infrastructure Windows Server and Unix, network storage
- email server Microsoft Exchange
- applications Install, configure, troubleshoot, support
- hardware Asset management, maintenance, cabling
- customer support Education and issue resolution.

Page | 2 Deacon Mosley

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, OKLAHOMA STATE UNIVERSITY, 2007

Information Assurance and Forensics, 3.86 GPA, President's Honor Roll

ASSOCIATE OF SCIENCE, OKLHAOMA STATE UNIVERSITY, 2004

Information Technology, 3.8 GPA, President's, and Academic Honor Roll

ASSOCIATE OF ART, TULSA COMMUNITY COLLEGE, 2004

International Studies (China), 3.8 GPA, President's, and Academic Honor Roll

CERTIFICATIO

NS

MICROSOFT SQL SERVER ADMINSTRATOR (MCSE, MCITP)

2012

INFORMATION SYSTEMS SECURITY PROFESSIONAL

2007

Page | 3 Deacon Mosley